<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Formats</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="leaveLetter">"22-2-2014( Date ) \nChennai-03 (Place).

From
Archit Gupta (Your Name),
S.V.N.I.T sophomore (Who are You),
Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology (Name of the Institution),
Surat, 395007 (Location of the Institution).

To
The Principal (To whomsoever it may concern),
Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology (Name of the institute),
Surat, 395007.(Location of the institute)

Respected Sir,
As I was ( Reason of Leave )suffering from fever,I could not attend the class for the past (Duration of leave) 3 days (With effect from) 19-2-2014 to 21-2-2014. Kindly excuse me for my absence and convert the same into leave.I have also attached medical certificate for your reference.I would be highly obliged.

Thanking you,

Yours faithfully,
Archit Gupta

*Parent's signature

Attachment:Medical certificate


Note:*It is also necessary to have parent's signature at the end of the letter,if you are a minor, else your signature are also valid."</string>

        <string name="coverLetter">"(Your Name)
(email address)
(Phone number)
(Residential address)
15 February 2014
(Name of the Professor)
Professor
(Name of the B school or where you are applying)

Respected Sir,
I am a second year student of(branch) at(college name). I am looking for an internship under your able guidance in the field of (name of stream) during (start date to end date). I am currently working on a project which aims at (aim of the project)under(where you are working). It involves (things related to the stream you're applying). Therefore, I can be of some help in your day-to-day research works.
(Try to explain why you are fit for the internship in this paragraph. If you're a 9 pointer, do mention it here.)
I would be really honoured if I have the privilege to work under a professor of an excellent stature as you. If it is possible, please consider me for the position of an intern.

Yours Sincerely,
(Your Name),
Sophomore (Your Year),
MANIT,Bhopal.(Your Institution and Location)"
</string>

    <string name="formalLetter">"
    Conventions
    There are a number of conventions that should be adhered to and it is important that the overall structure is as clear and concise as possible and that you avoid the use of colloquialisms (informal language).

    Addresses:
    1) Your Address
    Your address should be displayed in the top right-hand section. This will enable the person that you are writing to, to reply.
    2) The Address of the person you are writing to
    This address should be displayed beneath your address on the left-hand side, remember to include the name of the person that you are writing to (if known).

    Date:
    This should be displayed on the right-hand side of the page on the line beneath your address and should be written in full format:
    e.g. 1st January 2001

    Salutation And Greeting:
    1) Dear Sirs,
    If you do not know the name of the person that you are writing to, use the greeting "Dear Sirs,". In some circumstances it is useful to find a name, especially if you are making a request as this will show that you have done your homework and you are more likely to receive a response.
    2) Dear Mr Jones,
    If you know the name, use one of the following titles:
    Mr - for a male
    Mrs - for a married female
    Miss - for an unmarried female
    Ms - for a female whose status is unknown or would prefer to remain anonymous
    Dr - for a person with the status of a doctor
    This should be followed by the surname only (not the first name).

    Concluding:
    1) Yours faithfully,
    If you do not know the name of the person, conclude with 'Yours faithfully,'.
    2) Yours sincerely,
    If you know the name of the person, conclude with 'Yours sincerely,'.
    3) Your signature
    Sign your name, then print it underneath the signature. If it is potentially unclear what your title would be then include this in brackets next to your printed name.

    Content
    In modern society there is a trend to use a shorthand writing style, for instance replacing the word 'you' with 'u' or replacing the word 'weekend' with 'wkend', there are many other examples. This casual approach and informal writing style can easily be transferred, sometimes subconsciously, when a more formal style is required.

    Introductory Paragraph
    The introductory paragraph should be concise and should clearly state the purpose, whether it is to lodge a complaint, make an enquiry or to request something.

    Main Body
    The main body should clearly state the points that you want to make. As a general rule it is a good idea to keep this as to the point as possible to ensure that the recipient remains engaged. A longer main body may be more appropriate when making a complaint as you may require to add more detail in order to convey the importance of what you are putting across.

    Concluding Paragraph
    The concluding paragraph should outline what action you would like the recipient to take: to make a refund, to send you information etc.

    Application
    Complaint
    A letter of complaint is sent to an individual or organisation in response to receiving poor service or a product that is not fit for purpose. An example of a letter of complaint would be a one sent to a tour operator who has provided a bad service while you have been on holiday. This does not necessarily need to be concise as it is important that you detail your arguments and points as much as possible.
    Enquiry
    A letter of enquiry makes an approach to an individual or organisation either speculatively or in response to printed public domain material whereby you are requesting some information. An example of a letter of enquiry would be one sent to a company requesting a copy of their catalogue or brochure. By their very nature these are short and to the point, it is usually beneficial to include other methods of contact in case the company needs to get in touch with you via other means.
    Request
    A letter of request is similar to when you make an enquiry but specifically asks an individual or organisation to take an action. An example of a letter of request would be one sent to request sponsorship for a charity activity. It is important to stress the importance of being clear and concise with this format as the recipient must remain engaged and interested in what you have to say."

    </string>
    <string name="TextI_1">"
    1. Analyse publications you enjoy reading. Consider magazines you have a subscription to or enjoy reading on a regular basis. You may also focus on publications you know little about but would like to start contributing articles to. Read at least three to four recent issues of the publications, with a close eye on several aspects:
•	Check if the bylines match the names on the masthead. If the names on the bylines do not match the masthead names, this may be an indication that the publication hires freelance writers to contribute to its issues.
•	Look for the names and contact information of editors for specific areas. If you’re interested in writing about pop culture, identify the name and contact information of the arts editor. If you’re more interested in writing about current events, look for the name and contact information of the managing editor or the features editor. You should avoid contacting the executive editor or the editor-in-chief as they are too high up the chain and you will likely not interact with them as a freelance writer.
•	Note recent topics or issues covered in the publication and the angle or spin on the topics. Does the publication seem to go for more controversial takes on a topic or a more objective approach? Does the publication seem open to experimentation in form and content or are they more traditional?
•	Look at the headlines used by the publication and how the articles begin.
•	Note the types of sources quoted in the articles.
•	Pay attention to how writers wrap up their articles in the publication.

    </string>

    <string name="TextI_2">"2.Consider recent trends or topics you talked about with a friend or peer. If you’ve had a good conversation about a trend, topic, or issue with a friend recently, think about how you may be able to take this conversation and turn it into a story idea. Maybe your friend was discussing a new trend on social media or how racism is a problem at her daughter’s school. Focus on conversations that were full of passion or strong emotion and that relate to a current issue or trend.
•	These inspiring conversations do not need to be about global problems or about a large issue. Having conversations with your neighbours, your friends, and your peers can allow you to discuss local topics that could then turn into an article idea for a local magazine.”

    </string>

    <string name="TextI_3">"3.Look up upcoming events in your area. If you are thinking of writing a magazine article for a local publication, you should look through local event listings for any events that may be newsworthy. This could be a local protest, restaurant openings, local plays, or local music festivals. Starting small with local publications before you branch out to national publications could help you get started as a magazine writer, especially if you are just starting your writing career.
•	You should also look through your local newspaper for human interest stories that may have national relevance. You could then take the local story and pitch it to a magazine. You may come across a local story that feels incomplete or full of unanswered questions. This could then act as a story idea for a magazine article.”

    </string>

    <string name="TextI_4">"4.Consider what other writers are publishing. You should have a good sense of what other writers are currently writing about or posting on social media. This way, you will not miss any current ideas or trends and may be able to put a different spin on an existing article.
    •	You can also set your Google alerts to notify you if key words on topics of interest appear online. If you have Twitter or Instagram, you can use the hashtag option to search trending topics or issues that you can turn into article ideas.”
    </string>

    <string name="TextI_5">"5.Think of a new angle on a familiar topic. Perhaps you are really interested in a topic that has been written to death in many different publications, but you can’t stop thinking about the topic. Look for a new angle on the topic so it feels fresh, relevant, and new. This will make your magazine article stand out to editors and engage your target audience.
    •	For example, rather than write about the psychological problems of social media on teenagers, which has been done many times in many different magazines, perhaps you can focus on a demographic that is not often discussed in relation to social media: seniors and the elderly. This will give you a fresh approach to the topic and ensure your article is not just regurgitating a familiar angle.”
    </string>


    <string name="Text2_1">"1.Research your article idea using sources like books and published texts. One of the key elements of a good magazine article is good research. Take the time to locate good sources and read any necessary supplementary material to help you get a better sense of the article idea. Read through research material like articles, books, video, and social media posts. Good quotes from sources can often make or break your credibility as a writer and lead to a stronger article.
•	Look for content written by experts in the field that relates to your article idea. If you are doing a magazine article on dying bee populations in California, for example, you should try to read texts written by at least two bee experts and or a beekeeper who studies bee populations in California.
•	You should ensure any texts you use as part of your research are credible and accurate. Be wary of websites online that contain lots of advertisements or who are not affiliated with a professionally recognized association or field of study. Make sure you check if any of the claims made by an author have been disputed by other experts in the field or have been challenged by other experts. Try to present a well-rounded approach to your research so you do not appear biased or slanted in you research.”
    </string>

    <string name="Text2_2">“2.Locate individuals who could be good sources. Think about individuals who may have interesting things to say about your topic and who can offer an expert opinion on your topic. You may also want to use consumers or clients as sources, depending on your topic. Do not be afraid to get on the phone and start calling people for interviews. Most people like to talk about themselves or about a topic they enjoy and are well versed in. You can also steal sources from other articles, as there is no rule against this if the sources are named in the article.
    •	You can also do an online search for individuals who may serve as good expert sources based in your area. If you need a legal source, you may ask other freelance writers who they use or ask for a contact at a police station or in the legal system.”
    </string>



    <string name="Text2_4">"4.Transcribe your interviews. Most editors will require you to transcribe all interviews in full in a word processing document and have it available in the event a source needs to be confirmed or a quote needs to be checked. Your magazine article will be fact checked by the magazine's fact checking team before it is sent to print and the fact checkers may require your transcribed interviews as a way to confirm quotes and sources.
    •	The best way to transcribe your interviews is to sit down with headphones plugged into your tape recorder and set aside a few hours to type out the interviews. There is no short and quick way to transcribe, unless you decide to use a transcription service, which will charge you a fee for transcribing your interviews.”
    </string>

    <string name="Text2_5">“5.Create an article outline. Before you dive into writing the article, you should set aside some time to create an outline. Read over your research, including your interview notes. Highlight any good quotes from your sources and key pieces of information from your research. You can then lean on these to create the article outline.
    •	Your outline should include the main point or angle of the article in the introduction, followed by supporting points in the article body, and a restatement or further development of your main point or angle in your conclusion section.
    •	The structure of your article will depend on the type of article you are writing. If you are writing an article on an interview with a noteworthy individual, your outline may be more straightforward and begin with the start of the interview and move to the end of the interview. But if you are writing an investigative report, you may start with the most relevant statements or statements that relate to recent news and work backward to the least relevant or bigger picture statements.
    •	Keep in mind the word count of the article, as specified by your editor. You should keep the first draft within the word count or just above the word count so you do not lose track of your main point. Most editors will be clear about the required word count of the article and will expect you not to go over the word count, for example, 500 words for smaller articles and 2,000-3,000 words for a feature article. Most magazines prefer short and sweet over long and overly detailed, with a maximum of 12 pages, including graphics and images.
    •	You should also decide if you are going to include images or graphics in the article and where these graphics are going to come from. You may contribute your own photography or the publication may provide a photographer. If you are using graphics, you may need to have a graphic designer recreate existing graphics or get permission to use the existing graphics.”
        </string>

    <string name="Text2_6">“6.Use a hook first line. A strong magazine article will draw a reader in and hook them from the first line. In fact, the lead paragraph of your article is considered the most important paragraph in your entire article. You can generate a hook first line to engage and inspire your readers in several different ways.
    •	Use an interesting or surprising example: This could be a personal experience that relates to the article topic or a key moment in an interview with a source that relates to the article topic. For example, you may start an article on beekeeping in California by using a discussion you had with a source: "Darryl Bernhart never thought he would end up becoming the foremost expert on beekeeping in California."
    •	Try a provocative quotation:
    •	Use a vivid anecdote: An anecdote is a short story that carries moral or symbolic weight. Think of an anecdote that might be a poetic or powerful way to open your article. For example, you may relate a short story about coming across abandoned bee hives in California with one of your sources, an expert in bee populations in California.
    •	Come up with a thought provoking question: Think of a question that will get your reader thinking and engaged in your topic, or that may surprise them. For example, for an article on beekeeping you may start with the question: "What if all the bees in California disappeared one day?"”
    </string>

    <string name="Text2_7">“7.Weave in quotes from experts or reliable sources. You should tailor the article’s language and tone to the target audience of the magazine and use the writing style of previously published articles in the publication as a guide. Make sure you weave in relevant and strong quotes from your sources, such as an expert source or a quote from another text.
    •	You want to avoid leaning too much on quotations to write the article for you. A good rule of thumb is to expand on a quotation once you use it and only use quotations when they feel necessary and impactful. The quotations should support the main angle of your article and back up any claims being made in the article.”
    </string>

    <string name="Text2_8">“8.End on a strong concluding statement that illuminates or expands on your article topic. You should try to end your first draft with a concluding statement that leaves the reader satisfied but also curious about further developments on the topic. Go for an ending that leaves the reader asking, “What next?” and do not try to answer all the questions raised by your article topic. Instead, look for ways to wrap up the article in an interesting, open ended way.
    •	You may want to lean on a strong quote from a source that feels like it points to future developments relating to the topic or the ongoing nature of the topic. Ending the article on a quote may also give the article more credibility, as you are allowing your sources to provide context for the reader.”
    </string>


    <string name="Text3_3">“.Revise the article for flow and structure. A good magazine article will flow well, with good transitions between paragraphs and good sentence structure. Try reading the article out loud to yourself or to a sympathetic audience. Note if any of the sentence structure sounds awkward or wordy. Be willing to removing or reworking large chunks of text so that the article flows and you have strong sentence structure throughout the article.”
    </string>

    <string name="Text3_4">“.Turn in the revised article by the deadline. Make sure you hit your deadline and turn in the article on time, especially if you are turning in your first article for the publication. If possible, turn the article in early to impress the editor and show you can meet deadlines for future articles for the publication.
    •	Most publications accept electronic submissions of articles. Talk with your editor to determine the best way to submit the revised article.”
    </string>

    <string name = "lifestyle">"    LIFESTYLE CHECK
    Lifestyle inflation is the increase in the amount expended by a person to support their needs.  Lifted from the economic concept of inflation in commodities, with lifestyle inflation, a person spends more and more for the same need as he progresses in life. From a generic pair of shoes, to Nike, to Italian leather oxfords.  From PB and J, to Subway, to gourmet breakfasts.  Lifestyle inflation per se is not necessarily evil.  After all, we work hard so we deserve something better, right?  Totally agreed.  It’s just that lifestyle inflation takes a dangerous turn when the rate of our increase in spending substantially differ from the rate of increase in our income.
Say, you got a raise of $200 starting next month, so in honor of your accomplishment, you decide to ditch your instant coffee for some daily Starbucks for $8.  For easier computation, in 4 weeks, you spent $160 on coffee. Okay, let us subtract your previous cost on instant coffee of $20, thus giving us a raise of $140 on coffee expense.  It is still within budget.  But did you upgrade just your coffee? You could also have rewarded yourself with a weekly spa, a new membership in the gym, etc.  All obliterating your income increase.
Lifestyle inflation has been cited by personal development coaches as one of the obstacles for maximizing one's potential.  As earlier illustrated, if the inflation is not controlled, it wreaks havoc on finances.  A messed up financial life equals serious troubles in other areas.  So before we get into serious trouble, here are ways to keep the inflation at a slow incline.
First, wedge your salary increases.  Renowned speaker Brian Tracy in several of his books espoused wedging salary increases, bonuses, and other extra income that comes your way.  This means that for every increase you get, set aside a chunk of it for savings to be forgotten until a genuine financial need arises.  The rest of the increase can be used to upgrade your needs.  You reward yourself but not at the expense of your future and net worth.
Second, do not count the chicks while the eggs are not hatched.  Often, we overflow with optimism that we start spending our future income on “sure close” deals or “I got it in the bag” gigs.  But they fizzle out.  The old adage that too much of something is bad is true.  So while you hope for the best, plan for the worst.  Do not live the life you cannot afford yet.
Third, stop keeping up with the Joneses.  Stanley and Danko’s “The Millionaire Next Door” revealed that most millionaires do not necessarily have the best of the luxury items the world can offer.  In fact, most lived in middle class neighborhoods and drove reliable Fords.  You have a choice.  Do you want to look rich or do you want to be rich.  Do not purchase products or secure services just because it is the hype, or because so-and-so already has it.
Fourth, and more importantly, know what your need is.  This is connected to the preceding suggestion.  For example, you’ve been wanting a BMW badly you would work 18 hours each day for weeks on end.  But take a step back.  What about a BMW do you want?  Is it because you need a means of transportation?  Is it because the rest of your social group has it? Is it because it will get you more clients for your practice? This is not saying do not buy the BMW.  Just know the reason for your need, a means of transportation, acceptance, a strategy to increase income.  Then make a proper decision.
We all envision ourselves decked in better garments, lounging in better homes, living a better life.  Hence, lifestyle inflation is normal.  As we upgrade, keep moderation in mind.  View your lifestyle from a higher perspective, seeing how it interplays with other aspects of your life.
Living a great life costs less than we compute it to be. "
</string>

    <string name = "sports">"Sample Sports Article

The Best Game the Fins Ever Played


Last game of the season and it is all over for our ‘fish friends’.

The 2-time division champion Tiger Paws of Taran Hills High were set to defend their title for the third time against the season upsetters Kingfisher Fins of Fillmore High. This is the first time the Fins were able to reach the championship tier in 15 years. The way they fought to reach that spot is nothing short of a feat. On the west side were the Fins wearing their sky blue shirts. Definitely smaller in number compared to the Paws but you can see the pride on their faces, cheering for their team.

For the very first time in Taran Hills High history, home team was introduced first. Crowd broke into their loudest cheers as the players, coaches and supporting staff rushed to the court. The team beaming at the crowd as they cheered. And then there were the Fins. I mentioned this is the last game of the season, but also the last game for the Fins. With issues regarding what pen-pushers on the office won’t do, Fillmore High’s sport and recreational fund was cut just when they were excelling. This was the Fins’ last game, ever. As sad as it is, that was not seen on the team that was also greeted with a thunderous cheer when they came out. You can see the determination on their faces, you can see the hunger to strive which is definitely the doing of their head coach Bob Powers, who announced his retirement after hearing about funding cuts.

Game starts and the Paws were the first to score. First quarter went by so quick and as the buzzer rang, it was the Paws leading, 22-14. Second quarter and you see both team captains pushing their hardest. The Fins’ captain Kevin Smith scored 9 points and 8 points for Tigers’ Robert Walt. Score was 38-24. Halftime and the Tigers performed their famous drumline routine while the Fins delighted the stands with a 12-piece band that got people singing and dancing on their feet.

Game resumed and the energy on the court changed. The Fins were the first out from the back. There was a short pause before the Paws came out but the court erupted as soon as they ran out. Cheers became louder when the stands noticed that the Paws are now wearing the Fillmore High’s blue shirts underneath their jerseys. An homage to a great team. The Paws were stunned from what they saw but cheered louder still. On the sides was Fins’ Coach Powers tipping his ball cap to the Paws’ Coach Phil Leibermann. It’s the Paws’ salute to the Fins and everyone on the court knew it.

Third quarter ended and the Fins noticeably fought harder against the Paws closing in at 55-47. Before the last quarter began, the Fins were shoulder to shoulder with Coach Powers’ very last hurrah. As the Fins said their last “Go Fins, SWIM!”, the crowd proudly cheered them on. It was at that moment when the line between the Paws and the Fins got blurred and everyone was just cheering for a great and unforgettable match.
The game ended 77-70, Fins for the win. Fins’ Coach Powers walked toward his team clapping as everyone huddled in the middle. Emotion was high and unmistakable.
When the emotions settled down, Coach Powers took the court with a mic and said “Thank you very much for the best game my Fins ever played.” which was followed with the loudest roar for the very last time."
    </string>

    <string name = "food">"
    Sample Food Magazine Article

    Contrary to what my Italian grandmother might tell you, when it comes to cooking (even Italian cooking) the first rule is, there are no rules. None. Zero. Forget all the rules you’ve ever been told, except of course the ones dealing with food safety. On second thought, make that safety in general. Not running with knives is pretty much always a good rule to follow.
    Those of us with culinary training are often the most guilty when it comes to foolishly chaining ourselves to some set of unwritten rules. We fear we will be committing some kind of unforgivable kitchen faux pas that we might never overcome. In doing so, we often commit an even worse offense: that of failing to think outside of the culinary box. That just won’t work in a time when creativity is almost as important as taste when critiquing cuisine.
    In today’s world of fusion cuisine and other eclectic practices, it’s fairly safe to say that almost anything goes. Take, for instance, traditional food and wine pairings. Everyone knows that red pairs with meats and that white should accompany fish, right? Wrong. Or perhaps simply short-sighted. One could just as easily err by serving a light white wine alongside a fish whose spicy flavor overpowers the vino. A better suggestion is to match textures and flavors. Serve a bold wine alongside a rich dish. Pair a high-acid wine with an acidic food such as a tomato- or vinegar-based dish. In fact, the sauce is an even bigger key to the correct pairing than is the actual meat itself. But then again, aren’t we abandoning convention altogether? Bottom line: Choose wines based on what you like and what your palette tells you works for the dish.
    Italians have also traditionally believed that pasta is a dish that should stand alone. Penne doesn’t belong next to a steak. Spaghetti and chicken parmesan shouldn’t be served on a plate together. Says who? Apparently the Olive Garden chain of restaurants didn’t get the memo. Neither did the millions of people who come in on a daily basis to sample their Tour of Italy entree.
    Another particularly Italian no-no is the centuries-old commandment of not topping fish with cheese. Although there is much debate about where this rule came from (explanations range from geographical to religious to safety reasons), no one can say why it is still in practice. While it’s true that the sharp, salty taste of many cheeses can easily overwhelm a mild fish, no one should be denied a well-prepared parmesan-crusted tilapia or salmon with goat cheese. And on a related note, there is no reason to withhold bacon from your fish dish either.
    The only real rule to observe is to do what make sense. Cook what you like. Eat what makes you happy. Taste as you go. Tweak when it’s needed. And learn from your mistakes. And, if your Italian grandmother has anything to say about it, just threaten to take her to Olive Garden."
     </string>

    <string name = "fashion">"
    Sample Fashion Magazine Article

    As the days begin to get longer and the sunshine starts to peek through the snowy haze, shorts and sandals have begun to make their way onto runways and sales floors. Though winter is still upon us, spring is getting closer every day. It’s time to thaw out and get to the mall to start filling your wardrobe with the most essential looks for the upcoming season.
    One overarching trend that’s visible throughout many of the spring lines is bold contrast. This can be seen in the form of bold stripes and even head-to-toe black and white combinations. The contrast can be reminiscent of ‘80s color blocking, a carryover from 2012, especially when paired with a denim jacket or retro-wash jean. In navy, it can also be nautical-themed.
    Full skirts—on dresses or alone—are also hot for spring. The look to aim for is slim at the shoulders with an A-line skirt that is a bit on the short side. Bold colors are a hit here as well. A contrasting cardigan makes an excellent partner for this piece, as do flats or low heels, which replace the four-inch stilettos of years past. Pointy-toed shoes will also make a comeback for the first time since the late ‘90s.
    Embellishments are everywhere this spring. From beads to sequins to stitching, the patterns are inspired by a variety of cultures. Asian designs, Indian motifs, and even just a simple trim help the most basic garment transition easily from daytime to evening wear.
    Another trend that is emerging on the spring scene is cut-outs. From large geometric shapes to small perforated openings, almost like a snowflake, skin is peeking through in a variety of places. While this trend is generally tastefully done, there may still be some who are hesitant to bare even a little more skin than they’re accustomed to. A suggestion is to pair this look with another popular look, sheer layers. A overlay of gauzy fabric, particularly white, will be seen frequently in combination with the cut-outs.
    A few trends that we failed to mention include bra tops, drop waist dresses, and plastic outerwear. While perhaps not for everyone, even these fads can look great if done right. See our how-to guide that appears later in this issue for more tips on how to wear these and other trends. But always remember that the best look is the one that makes you feel comfortable in your own skin. Don’t make yourself a slave to fashion at the sacrifice of what suits you best. As Coco Chanel herself so eloquently stated, “Fashion fades; only style remains the same.” And wearing clothes that fit and flatter is always in style."
    </string>

    <string name = "literary">"
Sample Literary Magazine Article

In today’s world of social networking, blogs, clouds, and all manner of hyperconnectivity, it seems as if anyone can be a writer—or at least call themselves one. It’s as simple as typing a paragraph and hitting Submit, and suddenly one is published. At least in the cyber-sense of the word. On a more conventional note, the mere mention of terms such as “blogosphere” and “tweet” can be almost enough to make a serious writer’s skin crawl. To see their craft dumbed down to its most basic form, the arranging of letters and words into (mostly) cohesive sentences, seems to some as a stab in the proverbial back. Many aspects of this social writing trend are quite controversial among writers. Please allow me to address a few.
I’ll start with the grammar, or what some consider to be the lack thereof. The nature of texting, updating statuses, and churning out content with alarming frequency has spawned the development of acronyms such as “OMG,” “BTW,” and “IMO,” to name a few. While these terms are considered unprofessional by most, it’s worth mentioning that there was a time when the use of the word “fax” (as opposed to facsimile) would prompt the raising of some eyebrows. Times change, and it is often necessary for people to do the same. On the flip side, it almost seems as if all rules of the English language have been completely thrown to the wind. Things that would have never flown in a freshman-level college English class are suddenly perfectly acceptable in cyberspace.
Almost as contentious as the grammatical nature of many social writing entries is their subject matter. Bloggers and other self-proclaimed writers laud the wholesomeness of their diets, the antics of their offspring, and sometimes just the mundane minutiae of their day-to-day life. Their topics are often uninteresting at best and completely narcissistic at worst. Then again, no one is required to read them, are they? Well, that depends. Many individuals who contribute to blogs and other sites frequently post links to their articles. They encourage others to link to their pages and offer giveaways and other incentives to readers. This can annoy those who feel compelled to continue to read their virtual trainwreck. However, on the other hand, who can blame them for wanting to monetize their hobby?
Another topic up for debate is the speed with which these writers post. Many update their sites two or more times per day. This is amidst a busy schedule of training for marathons, changing dirty diapers, and creating a vignette to grace the table of a lovely Thanksgiving dinner. While many writers pride themselves on the way they agonize over the selection of each word, these would-be authors churn out several paragraphs in just a few short minutes. Who’s to say whether they should be applauded for their swiftness or scolded for their lack of careful editing?
While one can easily debate the necessity or authenticity of this newest entry onto the writing scene, one can not yet question their staying power. It’s clear that this form of writing is here to stay, at least for now, and should either be embraced or politely eluded. IMO, it is often best to take the high road."
    </string>


</resources>
